<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.2//EN" "http://apache.org/forrest/dtd/document-v12.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>jUDDI CVS Repository</title>
  </header>
  <body>

    <section>
      <title>CVS Repository</title>
      <p>Most users of the source code probably don't need to have day to day access 
        to the source code as it changes. For these users we provide easy to unpack 
        source code downloads via our <link href="releases.html">download pages</link>.
      </p>
      <p><b><font size="+1">View the Source Tree</font></b><br/>
      </p>
      <p>The latest CVS sources can be viewed at <link href="http://cvs.apache.org/viewcvs/ws-juddi/">http://cvs.apache.org/viewcvs/ws-juddi/</link>
      </p>      

      <p>
        <b><font size="+1">Access the Source Tree (AnonCVS)</font></b><br />
         So, you've decided that you need access to the source tree
        to see the latest and greatest code. There's two different
        forms of CVS access. The first is anonymous and anybody can
        use it. The second is not and you must have a login to the
        development server. If you don't know what this means, join
        the <link href="lists.html">mailing list</link> and find out.
      </p>
      <p>
        Anyone can checkout source code from our anonymous CVS
        server. To do so, simply use the following commands (if you
        are using a GUI CVS client, configure it appropriatly):
      </p>
      
<source>
cvs -d :pserver:anoncvs@cvs.apache.org:/home/cvspublic login
password: anoncvs
      
cvs -d :pserver:anoncvs@cvs.apache.org:/home/cvspublic checkout ws-juddi
</source>
  
      <b><font size="+1">Full Remote CVS Access</font></b> <br />
      If you are a <i>Committer</i> and have a login on the Apache
      development server, this section is for you. If you are not a
      Committer, but you want to submit patches or even request
      commit privelages, please see the <link
      href="http://jakarta.apache.org/site/guidelines.html">Jakarta
      GuideLines</link> page (we follow the same rules) for more
      information. 
      <p>
        To have full access to the CVS server, you need to follow the
        links depending on the operating system you are using:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <link
          href="http://jakarta.apache.org/site/cvsonunix.html">Unix</link>
        </li>
        <li>
          <link
          href="http://jakarta.apache.org/site/cvsonwin32.html">Windows</link>
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>
