<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!--
 * Copyright 2001-2009 The Apache Software Foundation.
 *
 * Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
 * you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
 * You may obtain a copy of the License at
 *
 *      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 *
 * Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
 * distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
 * WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
 * See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
 * limitations under the License.
 *
 */ -->

<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "jUDDI_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<!-- chapter: Authentication -->
<chapter id="chap-Authentication">
    <title>Authentication</title>
    
    <!-- section: Introduction -->
    <section id="sect-authentication_intro">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <para>
        In order to enforce proper write access to jUDDI, each request to jUDDI needs a
        valid <classname>authToken</classname>. Note that read access is not restricted
        and therefore queries into the registries are not restricted.
        </para>
        
        <para>
        To obtain a valid <classname>authToken</classname> a
        <methodname>getAuthToken()</methodname> request must be made, where a
        <classname>GetAuthToken</classname> object is passed. On the
        <classname>GetAuthToken</classname> object a <property>userid</property> and
        <property>credential</property> (password) needs to be set.
        </para>
            
       <programlisting language="Java"><xi:include href="extras/Authentication_1.java" parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" /></programlisting>

        <para>
        The property <property>juddi.auth</property> in the
        <filename>juddi.properties</filename> configuration file can be used to configure
        how jUDDI is going to check the credentials passed in on the
        <classname>GetAuthToken</classname> request. By default jUDDI uses the
        <classname>JUDDIAuthenticator</classname> implementation. You can provide your own
        authentication implementation or use any of the ones mention below. The
        implementation needs to implement the
        <interfacename>org.apache.juddi.auth.Authenticator</interfacename> interface, and
        <property>juddi.auth</property> property should refer to the implementation class.
        </para>

        <para>
        There are two phases involved in Authentication. The authenticate phase and the
        identify phase. Both of these phases are represented by a method in the
        <interfacename>Authenticator</interfacename> interface.
        </para>
        
        <para>
        The authenticate phase occurs during the <methodname>GetAuthToken</methodname>
        request as described above. The goal of this phase is to turn a user id and
        credentials into a valid publisher id. The publisher id (referred to as the
        “authorized name” in UDDI terminology) is the value that assigns ownership within
        UDDI. Whenever a new entity is created, it must be tagged with ownership by the
        authorized name of the publisher. The value of the publisher id can be completely
        transparent to jUDDI – the only requirement is that one exists to assign to new
        entities. Thus, the authenticate phase must return a non-null publisher id. Upon
        completion of the <methodname>GetAuthToken</methodname> request, an authentication
        token is issued to the caller.
        </para>
    
        <para>
        In subsequent calls to the UDDI API that require authentication, the token issued
        from the <methodname>GetAuthToken</methodname> request must be provided. This
        leads to the next phase of jUDDI authentication – the identify phase.
        </para>

        <para>
        The identify phase is responsible for turning the authentication token (or the
        publisher id associated with that authentication token) into a valid
        <classname>UddiEntityPublisher</classname> object. The
        <classname>UddiEntityPublisher</classname> object contains all the properties
        necessary to handle ownership of UDDI entities. Thus, the token (or publisher id)
        is used to “identify” the publisher.
        </para>

        <para>
        The two phases provide compliance with the UDDI authentication structure and grant
        flexibility for users that wish to provide their own authentication mechanism.
        Handling of credentials and publisher properties can be done entirely outside of
        jUDDI. However, jUDDI provides the Publisher entity, which is a sub-class of
        <classname>UddiEntityPublisher</classname>, to persist publisher properties within
        jUDDI. This is used in the default authentication and is the subject of the next
        section.      
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <!-- section:  -->
    <section id="sect-jUDDI_Authentication">
        <title>jUDDI Authentication</title>
        <para>
        The default authentication mechanism provided by jUDDI is the
        <classname>JUDDIAuthenticator</classname>. The authenticate phase of the
        <classname>JUDDIAuthenticator</classname> simply checks to see if the user id
        passed in has an associated record in the Publisher table. No credentials checks
        are made. If, during authentication, the publisher does not exist, it the
        publisher is added on the fly.
        </para>

        <warning>
            <para>
            Do not use jUDDI authentication in production.
            </para>
        </warning>

        <para>
        The identify phase uses the publisher id to retrieve the Publisher record and return
        it. All necessary publisher properties are populated as Publisher inherits from
        <classname>UddiEntityPublisher</classname>.
        </para>
        
        <programlisting language="Java"><xi:include href="extras/Authentication_2.java" parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" /></programlisting>

    </section>
    
    
    <!-- section: XMLDocAuthentication -->
    <section id="sect-XMLDocAuthentication">
        <title>XMLDocAuthentication</title>
        
        <para>
        The <classname>XMLDocAuthentication</classname> implementation needs a XML file on
        the classpath. The <filename>juddi.properties</filename> file would need to look
        like
        </para>
        
        <programlisting language="Java"><xi:include href="extras/Authentication_3.java" parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" /></programlisting>

        <para>
        where the name of the XML can be provided but it defaults to
        <filename>juddi-users.xml</filename>, and the content of the file would looks
        something like
        </para>
    
        <programlisting language="XML"><xi:include href="extras/Authentication_1.xmlt" parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" /></programlisting>

        <para>
        The authenticate phase checks that the user id and password match a value in the
        XML file. The identify phase simply uses the user id to populate a new
        <classname>UddiEntityPublisher</classname>.
        </para>
    
    </section>
    
    
    <!-- section: CryptedXMLDocAuthentication  -->
    <section id="sect-CryptedXMLDocAuthentication">
        <title>CryptedXMLDocAuthentication</title>

        <para>
        The <classname>CryptedXMLDocAuthentication</classname> implementation is similar
        to the <classname>XMLDocAuthentication</classname> implementation, but the
        passwords are encrypted
        </para>

        <programlisting language="Java"><xi:include href="extras/Authentication_4.java" parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" /></programlisting>

        <para>
        where the name user credential file is
        <filename>juddi-users-encrypted.xml</filename>, and the content of the file would
        looks something like
        </para>

        <programlisting language="XML" ><xi:include href="extras/Authentication_2.xmlt" parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" /></programlisting>

        <para>
        The <classname>DefaultCryptor</classname> implementation uses
        <literal>BEWithMD5AndDES</literal> and <literal>Base64</literal> to encrypt the
        passwords. Note that the code in the <classname>AuthenticatorTest</classname> can
        be used to learn more about how to use this Authenticator implementation. You can
        plugin your own encryption algorithm by implementing the
        <interfacename>org.apache.juddi.cryptor.Cryptor</interfacename> interface and
        referencing your implementation class in the <property>juddi.cryptor</property>
        property.
        </para>

        <para>
        The authenticate phase checks that the user id and password match a value in the XML
        file. The identify phase simply uses the user id to populate a new
        <classname>UddiEntityPublisher</classname>.
        </para>
        
    </section>
    
   <!-- section: LDAP Authentication -->
    <section id="sect-LDAP_Authentication">
        <title>LDAP Authentication</title>

        <para>
	<classname>LdapSimpleAuthenticator</classname> provides a way of authenticating
	users using Ldap simple authentication.    It is fairly rudimentary and more 
	LDAP integration is planned in the future, but this class allows you to authenticate
	a user based on an LDAP prinicipal, provided that the principal and the juddi publisher ID
	are the same.
        </para>

        <para>
        To use this class you must add the following properties to the
        <filename>juddi.properties</filename> file:
        </para>

        <programlisting language="XML"><xi:include href="extras/Authentication_5.xmlt" parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" /></programlisting>

        <para>
	The <classname>juddi.auth.url</classname> property configures the
        <classname>LdapSimpleAuthenticator</classname> class so that it knows where the LDAP
	server resides.     Future work is planned in this area to use the LDAP uid rather than
	the LDAP principal as the default publisher id.
        </para>

    </section>



    <!-- section: JBoss Authentication -->
    <section id="sect-JBoss_Authentication">
        <title>JBoss Authentication</title>

        <para>
        Finally is it possible to hook up to third party credential stores. If for example
        jUDDI is deployed to the JBoss Application server it is possible to hook up to
        it's authentication machinery. The <classname>JBossAuthenticator</classname> class
        is provided in the <filename>docs/examples/auth</filename> directory. This class
        enables jUDDI deployments on JBoss use a server security domain to authenticate
        users.
        </para>

        <para>
        To use this class you must add the following properties to the
        <filename>juddi.properties</filename> file:
        </para>

        <programlisting language="XML"><xi:include href="extras/Authentication_3.xmlt" parse="text" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" /></programlisting>

        <para>
        The <property>juddi.auth</property> property plugs the
        <classname>JbossAuthenticator</classname> class into the jUDDI the Authenticator
        framework. The <classname>juddi.sercuity.domain</classname>, configures the
        <classname>JBossAuthenticator</classname> class where it can lookup the
        application server's security domain, which it will use to perform the
        authentication. Note that JBoss creates one security domain for each application
        policy element on the
        <filename>$JBOSS_HOME/server/default/conf/login-config.xml</filename> file, which
        gets bound to the server JNDI tree with name
        <code>java:/jaas/&lt;application-policy-name&gt;</code>. If a lookup refers to a
        non existent application policy it defaults to a policy named other.
        </para>

    </section>
    
</chapter>
